<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oktomus | computer graphics</title>
    <link>https://oktomus.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on oktomus | computer graphics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 18:50:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oktomus.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Redirect any link on a GitHub pages website</title>
      <link>https://oktomus.com/posts/2019/github-pages-redirect-any-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 18:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oktomus.com/posts/2019/github-pages-redirect-any-link/</guid>
      <description>I recently switched my website from django to hugo. All the links referencing to my website are now broken and I need to deal with this.
 Tip: You can see all your website links that matter to google for referencing by searching for site:example.com in your search engine.
 When switching to hugo, I also decided to switch to gh-pages. While it&#39;s pretty nice for many reasons, it doesn&#39;t have any server-side configuration and we can&#39;t do proper URL redirection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swap escape and caps lock on Windows</title>
      <link>https://oktomus.com/posts/2018/swap-escape-caps-lock-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 21:39:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oktomus.com/posts/2018/swap-escape-caps-lock-windows/</guid>
      <description>So you want to switch the caps lock key with the escape key, but you don&#39;t want to edit the register. Don&#39;t worry ! This is fairly simple to do on windows, except that you will need to install a software if you want something that won&#39;t blow up. ¯\_(ツ)_/¯
Side note: If you are a vim user, this tip will change your life. For real.
You will need to install AutoHotkey, a lightweight application that allows you to make advanced modifications on your keyboard for specific application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Propagate shortcuts — key inputs — from dialogs to Maya with Qt</title>
      <link>https://oktomus.com/posts/2018/qt-propagate-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:37:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oktomus.com/posts/2018/qt-propagate-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>If you want to use Maya or any other application&#39;s shortcuts while you are using a custom tool, you need to propagate key events to the application. It can be useful with custom Qt dialogs and widgets.
To propagate a key event, you just need to ignore it in your widget or window.
class YourWidget(QtGui.QWidget): .... def keyPressEvent(self, event): if ... : event.accept() else: event.ignore() By default, the event is accepted, so accepting is useless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate models when adding inheritance in Django</title>
      <link>https://oktomus.com/posts/2017/migrate-models-when-adding-inheritance-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 21:28:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oktomus.com/posts/2017/migrate-models-when-adding-inheritance-django/</guid>
      <description>When you have one or more models that you are already using in your application and you want to change the parent class, the Django migration tool doesn&#39;t know what to do with the fields that will be transferred into the parent class values. By default, Django will erase existing fields and create new ones.
Here is a scheme a what you may want to do.
Changing the parent class is useful when you want to share some attributes and operations throughout multiple models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up a red light alarm to check your website status with python, cron and the Philips hue API</title>
      <link>https://oktomus.com/posts/2017/red-light-alarm-check-your-website-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 21:18:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oktomus.com/posts/2017/red-light-alarm-check-your-website-status/</guid>
      <description>Just to let you know, there are much better ways to monitor your services. But I found this quite funny to make and it&#39;s a first step on creating incredibly useful Hue apps \o/.
The result It seems that your browser doesn&#39;t support native HTML5 videos..
 A cron tab is set on the NAS which run my python script every minutes. The script then check for the website and if it&#39;s down, it makes the lamps blink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safely manage Blender&#39;s handlers while developing</title>
      <link>https://oktomus.com/posts/2017/safely-manage-blenders-handlers-while-developing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 21:06:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oktomus.com/posts/2017/safely-manage-blenders-handlers-while-developing/</guid>
      <description>What is a handler ? Handlers are basically callbacks that you create to execute a specific function every time something happens. Blender&#39;s API currently provide some handlers, frame_change_pre will be used in this article. Each handler is a list of functions, in this case, every function in frame_change_pre will be executed before a switch of frame.
The problem Let&#39;s say that you are working on your callback function, everytime you change your function you will have to add it in the handler list to be able to use it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>